I added the code that we were just looking at into our app.
我把我们刚刚看的代码加入到了应用中
It says View orderSummaryTextView = findViewById,
代码是 View orderSummaryTextView = findViewById
then we pass in the resource ID for the order_summary_text_view.
然后把资源 ID 传给 order_summary_text_view
But this causes an error in Android Studio on the next line.
但这样的话在 Android Studio 中下一行就会报错
It says it cannot resolve the method setText.
它说无法解析 setText 方法
If I add another line of code here,
如果我在这添加另一行代码
I can show you the types of methods that are valid on this variable.
它会显示这个变量中有效的方法类型
So, we just created the orderSummaryTextView variable here,
我们建立一个 orderSummaryTextView 变量
and it's a TypeView, and so
它是一个视图类型
on the next line, we should be able to call methods on it.
我们能在下一行调用它
But if you look at the autocomplete suggestions,
如果你看一下自动补全建议
these methods are actually View methods.
会发现这些方法实际上是视图方法
There's no TextView specific methods.
没有专门针对 TextView 的方法
For example, there's no setText method.
比如没有 setText 这个方法
That's why we get an error down here when we try to call setText.
这就是我们调用 setText 时会报错的原因
You also can't set text size, or set text color, or any of those.
你也不能设置尺寸 颜色 和其他属性
So where are all those methods?
那么那些方法都在哪？
Well, the thing is that a TextView is a more specific type of View.
其实 TextView 是一种更加具体的 View
So if we want to call TextView methods
所以如果你想在对象中调用 TextView 方法
on this object we need to make sure that this is a TextView object.
我们需要确保这是一个 TextView 对象
Okay. Now the variable is a TextView object.
现在这个变量是一个 TextView 对象
But then I get another error that says incompatible types, because a TextView
但是它报错了 它说这个类型不兼容 因为
is required on the right hand side, but we're finding just a regular view.
右边也必须是 TextView 但只找到一个常规 View
That's because the findViewById method returns a View.
因为 findViewById 方法返回的是常规 View
So how do we reconcile this?
怎么使它们一致呢？
Well, since TextView is a more specific type of View or put another way,
因为 TextView  是一个更具体的 View  换句话说
a TextView is a subclass of view, we can actually use something called casting.
TextView 是 View 类的一个子类 我们可以使用类型转换
Casting in Java means that we can take the View returned by this method and
在 Java 中类型转换意味着 我们可以把这个方法返回的 View
actually treat it as a TextView.
转换成一个 TextView
So now this right hand side is actually a TextView object, and
现在 右边已经是个 TextView  对象了
then we can store it inside this orderSummaryTextView variable.
然后把它存到 orderSummaryTextView 变量中
I know that this must be really overwhelming because I just mentioned
我知道你肯定觉得很迷惑 因为我刚刚
a ton of new concepts.
提到了太多新的概念
Let me try to explain again.
我们尝试解决一下
The findViewById method turns an object of type View.
findViewById 方法会把对象转化成视图类型
By writing this notation,
通过写这个标记
parentheses with the desired object data type in the middle of it.
也就是括号和里边的对象数据类型
We're casting this View into a TextView.
我们就把 View 转换成了 TextView
So the whole expression here evaluates to a TextView object.
所以整个表达式计算结果是一个 TextView 对象
Then, we can store that in the variable, on the left-hand side,
然后 我们可以存储到左边的变量里
which is orderSummary TextView, and it has a type TextView.
也就是 orderSummary 里 是 TextView 类型
Now, on subsequent lines, we can call TextView methods on this object.
在下一行 在这个对象中我们可以调用 TextView  方法
Do you see now how all the text methods are showing up here?
你看到展示在这的所有方法了吗？
setAllCaps, setTextSize, and more.
setAllCaps setTextSize 等等
So I can just erase this now, because setText should work,
删除这行 因为 setText 可以工作了
and there's no more errors.
没有报错
So if we want to be able to call TextView methods,
如果你想调用 TextView 方法
we need to have a TextView object.
我们需要有一个 TextView 对象
In order to have a TextView object, We need to call findViewById,
为了有一个 TextView 对象 我们需要调用 findViewById
and then cast this View object into a TextView.
然后把 View 转换成 TextView 格式
The reason why casting works is because
之所以转换后就可以工作了 是因为
this View here in the view hierarchy is actually a TextView.
在视图层级结构上这里的这个 View 确实是 TextView
If we we try to cast it into something like a radio button, that wouldn't work,
如果我们想转换成其他的 比如单选按钮 就不可以
because the orderSummaryTextView is actually a TextView, so
因为 orderSummaryTextView 是 TextView
we have to cast it into the appropriate type.
我们必须转换成合适的类型
Similarly, in the displayQuantity method, we're calling findViewById and
同样 在 displayQuantity 方法中 我们调用 findViewById
we're passing in this resource ID for the quantity TextView.
把资源 ID 传到 quantityTextView 中
This returns a View, and we cast it into a TextView, and
这会返回一个 View 并转化为 TextView
we can store that inside this variable called quantityTextView.
然后存放到 quantityTextView 变量中
This variable has type TextView, and so,
这个变量是 TextView 类型 所以
on subsequent lines, we can TextView methods on it, like setText.
在下一行 我们可以调用 TextView 方法 比如 setText
Here's the updated MainActivity code using casting.
这是通过类型转换更新的 MainActivity 代码
We can cast these Views into TextViews so that we can store them in variables
我们可以把这些 View 转换成 TextView 然后就可以把它们存到
that have type TextView so in this list of MainActivity variables,
TextView 变量中了 在 MainActivity 变量列表中
now quantityTextView and orderSummaryTextView are type TextView.
现在 quantityTextView  和 orderSummaryTextView  是 TextView 类型
We can call TextView methods on these,
可以用它们调用 TextView 方法
and we're not just limited to treating them as Views.
我们不能局限于仅把它们当做 View
And now we can call TextView specific methods on these variables.
现在我们可以用这些变量调用 TextView 专属方法
For example we can call setText on the orderSummaryTextView,
比如我们可以在 orderSummaryTextView 上调用 setText  方法
and we can call setText on the quantityTextView.
在 quantityTextView 上也能调用 setText 方法
As you can see,
正如你看到的
you have to be careful about what data types are being used where.
你必须注意在不同地方使用的数据类型
So far, when we've called methods, we haven't worried about the return value,
目前为止 在你调用方法时 我们还没考虑过返回值
because the setText method actually has no return value.
因为 setText 方法没有返回值
Same with the imageView.setImageResource method.
imageView.setImageResource 方法和它一样
This has no return value.
没有返回值
But other methods can have return values.
但是其他方法可以有返回值
For example, in the TextView class we have a getTextSize method.
比如在 TextView 类 我们有一个 getTextSize 方法
This returns an integer, so
它会返回一个整型
we can store the result of this method in a variable called size of type int.
所以我们可以把结果存到一个叫 size 的整型变量中
Here's another method that has a return value.
这是另一个带返回值的方法
In the Button class you can call the getHeight method,
在 Button 类中你可以调用 getHeight 方法
and this returns an integer value, so you can store it inside a variable.
这会返回一个整型 你可以把它存到一个变量里
If you tried to store this result inside a string, for example,
如果你想把它们存到字符串里
you would get an error, because this method returns an integer.
它会报错 因为方法会返回一个整型
In order to know what type of data needs to be passed into a method and what data
为了知道方法中传入的数据类型
type gets returned back from a method, you should check the documentation.
和方法返回的数据类型 你需要查阅文档
And for example, in the TextView class,
比如 TextView 类
if you call any of these methods, it returns a value of type int.
如果你调用这些方法中的任何一个 就会返回一个整型值
The return value data type is in the left-hand column here.
在左边这一列是返回数据类型
For other methods, you might get void as a return value, or booleans,
对于其他的方法 你可能会得到空的或布尔类型的返回值
which we haven't learned about yet, or floats or longs and etc.
这些我们还没学 还有浮点类型和长整型
This documentation page also shows what are the expected data types for
这个文档页面还展示了方法所要求的输入
the inputs for each method.
数据类型
For example, the setTextColor method requires an integer as input and
比如 setTextColor 方法要求输入整型
the return value is void, so there's no return value.
返回值是空 所以没有返回值
So check the documentation to know what data types are expected.
可以通过查阅文档来了解要求的输入数据类型
Otherwise, you'll get errors in Android Studio saying that
否则 Android Studio 就会报错
the data types don't match.
显示数据类型不匹配
Now it's your turn to practice.
现在该你练习了
Below are four different code examples.
这是四个不同的代码示例
Some of the code may contain errors relating to data types not matching.
有些代码可能出现数据类型不匹配的错误
If you find an error,
如果你找到了
describe how you're supposed to fix it by writing it in the boxes provided.
在下边的框里写一下如何解决
Otherwise, you can just write No error if the code is perfectly fine.
如果代码是完美的就写上没有错误
This is going to be challenging quiz because we just covered
这是一个具有挑战性的问题 因为
a lot of concepts, and this code is still pretty new to you.
里边涉及很多概念 这些代码对你来说也很陌生
Take your time and check the documentation for these methods.
可以通过查阅文档来学习这些方法
Make sure that the inputs and the return values are correct and
确保输入和返回值是正确的
that, if we're declaring variables, that we have the correct data types here.
如果声明变量 数据类型要正确
Also, look up the documentation for
也可以查阅这些方法的相关文档
these method calls to make sure that we're using the methods correctly.
来确保正确使用它们